Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we've got an intermediate level lesson all about going
我是Catherine，今天我们有一个中级课程，内容是关于去
to the beach.
海滩的。
That's right.
没错。
You know, it's a very popular thing to do, especially during the summer.
你知道，这是一件很受欢迎的事情，尤其是在夏天。
It's hot.
天气很热。
You want to go maybe to the beach to lay on the sand and maybe get some color.
你可能想去海滩，躺在沙滩上，也许晒黑一点。
And also swim in the ocean.
还可以在海里游泳。
Yeah.
是啊。
Yeah, it's a nice way to cool off when it's really hot in the summer.
是啊，夏天很热的时候，这是一种很好的降温方式。
That's right.
没错。
We're going to talk about the beach and a lot of vocab that we find related to this
我们要聊聊海滩，以及很多与这个
activity.
活动相关的词汇。
But before we get into the dialogue, we have a word for you on Vocabulary Preview.
但在进入对话之前，我们有一个词要给大家预览。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
So the keyword today here is jellyfish.
今天的关键词是水母。
Jellyfish.
水母。
So jellyfish is actually an animal, right?
水母其实是一种动物，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
It's a very dangerous animal.
它是一种很危险的动物。
It's a small little animal.
它是一种小动物。
So these things live in the water and they often live in shallow areas and they can sting
这些东西生活在水里，经常在浅水区，它们会蜇
you.
人。
That's right.
没错。
They look like little plastic bags with little strings attached to it.
它们看起来像小塑料袋，带着一些小细丝。
And they just float around and if you happen to touch one, it hurts a lot.
它们就漂浮着，如果你不小心碰到一个，会很疼。
Yeah, it can be very painful.
是啊，可能非常痛苦。
So jellyfish is our word today.
所以水母就是我们今天的词。
Let's take a listen to today's dialogue and we'll be back in a minute to talk more about
我们来听一下今天的对话，稍后回来再聊聊
what's going on.
发生了什么。
Oh George, what a beautiful day it is.
哦，乔治，今天天气真美。
The sun is hot and there are just a few clouds scattered here and there.
太阳很热，只有几朵云零星散布。
What a perfect day to be at the beach.
真是去海滩的完美一天。
The kids are going to have so much fun and we'll be able to relax in the sun while they're
孩子们会玩得很开心，我们也能在阳光下放松，而他们
playing.
在玩耍。
It does seem like the perfect day.
看起来确实是完美的一天。
I'm glad we chose to get out of the city and enjoy the nice weather.
我很高兴我们选择离开城市，享受好天气。
This looks like the perfect spot.
这看起来是个完美的地方。
Okay kids, put on your sunscreen while your mom and I set up camp.
好了孩子们，你们妈妈和我搭帐篷的时候，涂上防晒霜。
Here Mary, help me lay down these beach towels.
玛丽，来帮我铺好这些沙滩巾。
There we go.
好了。
Can you help me with the umbrella?
你能帮我撑伞吗？
Perfect.
完美。
Okay kids, here's a beach ball and a frisbee, a pail and a shovel.
好了孩子们，这里有一个沙滩球、一个飞盘、一个小桶和一把铲子。
I want to see an impressive sandcastle by the time we leave.
我希望在我们离开之前能看到一个令人印象深刻的沙堡。
Don't stray too far.
别走太远。
Wait, leave your sandals here or put on your wet shoes.
等等，把凉鞋留在这里，或者穿上湿鞋。
And stay in the shallow area.
待在浅水区。
I don't want to see you go any further than that sandbar.
我不希望你们游过那个沙洲。
It's too deep out there and we didn't bring your floaties.
那边太深了，而且我们没带你们的浮板。
You're back already?
你们这么快就回来了？
The water was too cold, huh?
水太冷了，是吧？
I'll tell you a secret.
我告诉你们一个秘密。
Do you see that small pool of water over there?
你们看到那边那个小水坑了吗？
It'll be warmer in there.
那里会更暖和。
Go see if you can find some seashells or catch some minnows.
去看看能不能找到一些贝壳，或者抓些小鱼。
Ah!
啊！
What is that?
那是什么？
A jellyfish?
水母吗？
Jeremy, put that down right now.
杰里米，马上放下那个。
It could sting you.
它会蜇你的。
Ah!
啊！
Not on me!
别扔到我身上！
Ah!
啊！
Alright, great, we're back.
好了，太好了，我们回来了。
So now why don't we take a look at four key words that we have prepared for you today
现在，我们来看看今天为你们准备的四个关键词
on Language Takeaway.
在语言要点部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
First up, we have a very important thing to bring to the beach, especially if you're like
首先，有一个去海滩非常重要的东西，特别是如果你像我一样
me and you burn easily.
容易晒伤。
So this thing is called sunscreen.
这个东西叫防晒霜。
Okay, sunscreen.
好的，防晒霜。
Now this is a liquid and you put it on your skin, right?
这是一种液体，涂在皮肤上，对吧？
And this protects you from the sun.
它能保护你免受阳光伤害。
So basically you put this cream all over your body to prevent sunburns, to prevent burning
基本上，你把这种霜涂遍全身，以防止晒伤，防止在
under the sun.
阳光下灼伤。
It's very important.
这非常重要。
So it's called sunscreen or also sometimes called sunblock.
所以它叫防晒霜，有时也叫防晒乳。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
Now we have our sunscreen and we arrive to the beach and one of the parents say, alright,
现在我们涂好防晒霜，到了海滩，其中一位家长会说，好了，
we're going to set up camp.
我们要安营扎寨了。
Okay, to set up camp.
好的，安营扎寨。
Well, this might be confusing because as many of you know, camp, camping, this is an activity,
嗯，这可能会让人困惑，因为你们很多人知道，camp、camping 是一项活动，
but we're not actually camping here.
但我们实际上不是在这里露营。
We're just going to be at the beach for one day.
我们只是要在海滩待一天。
So to set up camp means to organize or arrange ourselves in a place.
所以“安营扎寨”意思是组织或安排自己在某个地方。
So it's a colloquial way of saying we are going to organize the area where we're going
所以这是一种口语化的说法，表示我们要整理好要待的地方，
to spend the day.
度过这一天。
We're going to make ourselves comfortable.
我们要让自己舒服些。
So you set up camp.
所以你就安营扎寨。
So not necessarily that you're going to camp there, but that you're going to prepare the
所以不一定是要在那里露营，而是你要准备好
area.
那个区域。
So this could be used in many other different areas, right?
所以这可以用在很多其他不同的场合，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So sometimes when tickets for really popular concerts go on sale, people line up for days
所以有时候当热门演唱会的门票开售时，人们会提前几天排队，
before they can buy the tickets.
才能买到票。
Well, if you're in line, you maybe want to set up camp.
嗯，如果你在排队，你可能想安营扎寨。
That means make yourself comfortable, sit down, bring a book, open some food packages.
意思是让自己舒服些，坐下来，带本书，打开一些食物包装。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
So to set up camp.
所以就是安营扎寨。
And well, when we go to the beach, we want to sit down or lay down on the sand.
嗯，当我们去海滩时，我们想坐在或躺在沙滩上。
And in order to do this, we usually bring along beach towels.
为了做到这一点，我们通常会带上沙滩巾。
That's right, Marco.
没错，Marco。
So towels can be any kind of towel.
所以毛巾可以是任何类型的毛巾。
You have a towel in your bathroom or in your kitchen.
你浴室或厨房里有毛巾。
Basically a piece of cloth that you use to dry yourself.
基本上是一块用来擦干自己的布。
But the special kind of towel we bring to the beach is called, of course, a beach towel.
但我们带到海滩的特殊毛巾，当然就叫沙滩巾。
These are usually much bigger than normal towels.
这些通常比普通毛巾大得多。
Yeah, they're very, very big.
是的，它们非常大。
And this is usually because you want to lay down on the sand on top of this towel, right?
这通常是因为你想躺在沙滩上，在这条毛巾上面，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
And the last word that we have for language takeaway is a beach umbrella or just an umbrella.
我们语言要点部分的最后一个词是沙滩伞或只是伞。
That's right.
没错。
So maybe you're lying down on this big, comfortable, soft beach towel, and you're afraid of being
所以也许你躺在这条又大又舒服又柔软的沙滩巾上，你担心
under the sun too much.
在太阳下晒太多。
So an umbrella is a way to protect yourself from the sun.
所以伞是一种保护自己免受阳光照射的方式。
It provides shade.
它提供阴凉。
That's right.
没错。
So it's called an umbrella.
所以它叫伞。
Or usually if you want to distinguish between the umbrella you use for the rain, you can
或者通常如果你想区分下雨时用的伞，你可以
call it a beach umbrella.
叫它沙滩伞。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
And these are usually a lot bigger and you don't actually carry them around in your hand.
这些通常大得多，而且你实际上不会用手拿着它们。
You have to put them into the sand.
你必须把它们插进沙子里。
That's right.
没错。
So it stands alone.
所以它是独立站着的。
Okay.
好的。
So four key phrases there for you on language takeaway.
所以语言要点部分有四个关键短语。
Why don't we go back, listen to the dialogue again, and we'll be back shortly.
我们为什么不回去，再听一遍对话，我们很快回来。
Oh, George, what a beautiful day it is.
哦，George，今天天气多好啊。
The sun is hot and there are just a few clouds scattered here and there.
太阳很热，只有几朵云零星散布。
What a perfect day to be at the beach.
多么完美的海滩日啊。
The kids are going to have so much fun and we'll be able to relax in the sun while they're
孩子们会玩得很开心，我们也能在太阳下放松，而他们
playing.
在玩耍。
It does seem like the perfect day.
看起来确实是完美的一天。
I'm glad we chose to get out of the city and enjoy the nice weather.
我很高兴我们选择离开城市，享受好天气。
This looks like the perfect spot.
这看起来是个完美的地方。
Okay, kids, put on your sunscreen while your mom and I set up camp.
好了，孩子们，涂上防晒霜，我和你妈妈要安营扎寨了。
Here Mary, help me lay down these beach towels.
来，Mary，帮我铺好这些沙滩巾。
There we go.
好了。
Can you help me with the umbrella?
你能帮我弄一下伞吗？
Perfect.
完美。
Okay, kids, here's a beach ball and a frisbee, a pail and a shovel.
好了，孩子们，这是沙滩球和飞盘，一个小桶和一把铲子。
I want to see an impressive sandcastle by the time we leave.
我希望在我们离开之前看到一个令人印象深刻的沙堡。
Don't stray too far.
别走太远。
Wait, leave your sandals here or put on your wet shoes.
等等，把凉鞋留在这里，或者穿上湿鞋。
And stay in the shallow area.
待在浅水区。
I don't want to see you go any further than that sandbar.
我不想看到你们走到那个沙洲以外。
It's too deep out there and we didn't bring your floaties.
那边太深了，我们没带你的浮板。
You're back already?
你们这么快就回来了？
The water was too cold, huh?
水太冷了，是吧？
I'll tell you a secret.
我告诉你们一个秘密。
Do you see that small pool of water over there?
你看到那边那个小水坑了吗？
It'll be warmer in there.
那里会更暖和。
Go see if you can find some seashells or catch some minnows.
去看看能不能找到一些贝壳，或者抓几条小鱼。
Ah!
啊！
What is that?
那是什么？
A jellyfish?
水母吗？
Jeremy, put that down right now.
杰里米，马上把它放下。
It could sting you.
它可能会蜇你。
Ah!
啊！
Not on me!
别往我身上扔！
Ah!
啊！
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now we have five more words that we're going to take a look at in Language Takeaway
现在我们要在“语言小课堂”里再看五个词。
Part 2.
第二部分。
Language Takeaway
语言小课堂。
Okay, so there are lots of fun things to do at the beach.
好的，海滩上有很多好玩的事情可以做。
And today we're not going to be talking about all of them because there are too many things.
今天我们不会全部讲到，因为太多了。
But one fun activity is playing frisbee.
但一个有趣的活动是玩飞盘。
That's right, frisbee.
没错，飞盘。
So this is a thing.
这是一个东西。
It's an object, a frisbee.
它是一个物体，飞盘。
Or you also play frisbee.
或者你也可以说玩飞盘。
That's right.
没错。
So a frisbee itself is usually made of plastic and it's like a plate.
飞盘本身通常由塑料制成，像一个盘子。
And it's very light and you throw it to your friends and it sails through the air.
它很轻，你扔给朋友，它会飞过空中。
Right, it kind of flies along the air and then somebody else has to catch it.
对，它有点像在空中飞，然后别人得接住它。
That's right.
没错。
So you can play frisbee or throw the frisbee.
所以你可以说玩飞盘或扔飞盘。
It's very popular with people playing frisbee with their dogs, right?
人们和狗一起玩飞盘很流行，对吧？
You throw the frisbee and the dog chases it.
你扔飞盘，狗去追它。
Dogs love frisbee.
狗喜欢飞盘。
Alright, another great activity that usually we do when we go to the beach is we build
好的，另一个我们通常去海滩时做的好活动是堆沙堡。
sand castles.
沙堡。
Okay, so I'm a master sand castle builder.
好的，我可是堆沙堡的高手。
I'm a really big fan of this activity.
我非常喜欢这个活动。
Really?
真的吗？
Basically, you use water and sand to create castles.
基本上，你用水和沙子来建造城堡。
And obviously, you have to use tools like shovels and buckets.
显然，你得用铲子和桶之类的工具。
Otherwise, it might look kind of funny.
否则，它可能会看起来有点滑稽。
And this is actually such a popular activity that there are even competitions at times.
这实际上是一个非常受欢迎的活动，有时甚至会有比赛。
People will not only build castles or houses or structures but maybe a statue of some sort
人们不仅会建造城堡、房子或结构，还可能建造某种雕像。
or an animal or different things.
或者动物或不同的东西。
That's right or people.
没错，或者人像。
People, yeah.
人像，是的。
So sand castle.
所以是沙堡。
Okay.
好的。
And well, whenever we go to the beach, the ocean can be a little bit dangerous.
嗯，每当我们去海滩时，海洋可能有点危险。
And that's why in the dialogue, one of the parents told their kids to stay in the shallow
这就是为什么在对话中，一位家长告诉他们的孩子待在水的浅水区。
area of the water.
浅水区。
That's right.
没错。
So shallow is it describes depth.
所以“浅”是用来描述深度的。
So how deep something is.
也就是某物有多深。
Something is shallow, it's not very deep.
某物是浅的，就不太深。
So there's very little water.
所以水很少。
But if there's a lot of water, maybe if you swim and you can't touch your feet on the
但如果水很多，也许你游泳时脚碰不到地。
ground, we call that deep.
我们称之为深。
So shallow is very low water and deep is lots and lots of water.
所以浅是水很浅，深是水很多。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So you'll usually find this in the ocean.
所以你通常会在海洋里发现这个。
If you go further, further, further in, it'll get deeper and deeper and deeper.
如果你越走越远，水会越来越深。
And more and more dangerous.
而且越来越危险。
Right.
对。
And this is why the mom also told the kid to not pass that sandbar that was ahead.
这也是为什么妈妈还告诉孩子不要越过前面的沙洲。
Okay, sandbar.
好的，沙洲。
This is a piece of sand that basically rises very high in the water.
这是一块沙子，基本上在水里升得很高。
So usually when you're on the beach and you go into the water and it gets deeper and deeper
所以通常当你在海滩上，走进水里，水越来越深。
and then all of a sudden it gets high again and there's more sand.
然后突然又变浅了，有更多沙子。
And so that part that you can stand on, that sand out in the water, that's called a sandbar.
所以你能站在的那部分，水里的沙子，就叫沙洲。
It's almost like a little island.
它几乎像一个小岛。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
And as you said, usually it gets deeper, deeper, then you have the sandbar so it gets higher.
正如你所说，通常水越来越深，然后有沙洲，所以它变浅了。
But usually if you pass the sandbar, it's going to get really deep all of a sudden.
但通常如果你越过沙洲，它会突然变得非常深。
That's right.
没错。
So that's why the mother doesn't want her child to go past the sandbar.
所以这就是为什么妈妈不想让她的孩子越过沙洲。
Right.
对。
And as well, if you're ever swimming in a swimming pool in the ocean, it's always a
另外，如果你在海洋里游泳，如果你不太会游泳或者有孩子。
good idea if you don't know how to swim well or if you have children to take along little
带上小浮圈总是一个好主意。
floaties.
小浮圈。
Okay, floaties.
好的，小浮圈。
I like this word.
我喜欢这个词。
Floaties are plastic rings that you put around your arms or maybe around your stomach and
小浮圈是塑料环，你套在胳膊上或肚子周围。
they're filled with air.
它们里面充满空气。
Right.
对。
So when you go in the water, they help you float.
所以当你下水时，它们帮你浮起来。
Exactly.
没错。
So this is a very common thing to put on children because they don't know how to swim well.
所以这是很常见给孩子用的东西，因为他们不太会游泳。
So you put them little floaties on their arms or around their stomachs and then they can
你给他们戴上小浮圈在胳膊上或围在肚子上，这样他们就能
just float and they won't drown.
浮在水面上，不会溺水。
That's right.
对。
Floaties.
浮圈。
Very good.
很好。
So a lot of key words there are related to the fun of going to the beach.
所以这里很多关键词都和去海滩的乐趣有关。
Why don't we go back, listen to the dialogue for the very last time.
我们不如回去，再听一遍对话，最后一次。
Oh, George, what a beautiful day it is.
哦，乔治，今天天气真好啊。
The sun is hot and there are just a few clouds scattered here and there.
太阳很热，只有几朵云零星散布。
What a perfect day to be at the beach.
真是去海滩的完美日子。
The kids are going to have so much fun and we'll be able to relax in the sun while they're
孩子们会玩得很开心，我们也能在阳光下放松，而他们
playing.
在玩耍。
It does seem like the perfect day.
看起来确实是完美的一天。
I'm glad we chose to get out of the city and enjoy the nice weather.
我很高兴我们选择离开城市，享受好天气。
This looks like the perfect spot.
这看起来是个完美的地方。
Okay, kids, put on your sunscreen while your mom and I set up camp.
好了，孩子们，涂上防晒霜，我和你妈妈要搭营地了。
Here Mary, help me lay down these beach towels.
玛丽，来帮我铺好这些沙滩巾。
There we go.
好了。
Can you help me with the umbrella?
你能帮我撑伞吗？
Perfect.
完美。
Okay, kids.
好了，孩子们。
Here's a beach ball and a frisbee, a pail and a shovel.
这里有沙滩球、飞盘、桶和铲子。
I want to see an impressive sand castle by the time we leave.
我想在我们离开前看到一个令人印象深刻的沙堡。
Don't stray too far.
别走太远。
Wait, leave your sandals here or put on your wet shoes.
等等，把凉鞋留在这里，或者穿上湿鞋。
And stay in the shallow area.
待在浅水区。
I don't want to see you go any further than that sandbar.
我不想看到你们游过那个沙洲。
It's too deep out there and we didn't bring your floaties.
那边太深了，我们没带你们的浮圈。
You're back already?
你们这么快就回来了？
The water was too cold, huh?
水太冷了，是吧？
I'll tell you a secret.
我告诉你们一个秘密。
Do you see that small pool of water over there?
你看到那边那个小水坑了吗？
It'll be warmer in there.
那里会更暖和。
Go see if you can find some seashells or catch some minnows.
去看看能不能找到一些贝壳或捉些小鱼。
Ah!
啊！
What is that?
那是什么？
A jellyfish?
水母吗？
Jeremy, put that down right now.
杰里米，马上放下那个。
It could sting you.
它会蜇你的。
Ah!
啊！
Not on me!
别扔到我身上！
Ah!
啊！
All right, so beach activities.
好了，所以海滩活动。
You say you're a master sand castle builder.
你说你是沙堡建造大师。
I love building sand castles.
我喜欢建沙堡。
I won't say that I'm very good at it.
我不会说我非常擅长。
Maybe not a professional.
可能不是专业的。
But I do a pretty good sand castle.
但我建的沙堡还不错。
Do you like getting buried in the sand?
你喜欢被埋在沙子里吗？
I love it.
我喜欢。
Really?
真的吗？
Although it also scares me.
虽然也让我有点害怕。
Have you ever had someone maybe cover you with sand and then you can't move?
你有没有过别人把你埋在沙子里，然后你动不了？
Yeah.
有。
Yeah, so it's a little bit scary.
是啊，所以有点吓人。
Obviously I'm not very comfortable with having my head covered.
显然我不太舒服把头埋起来。
But some people even do that.
但有些人甚至那样做。
They cover their entire body, head to toe.
他们埋全身，从头到脚。
How do they breathe?
他们怎么呼吸？
And they have a straw out of their mouth to breathe.
他们嘴里插根吸管来呼吸。
Wow.
哇。
I actually love going to the beach and it's relaxing, it's really fun.
我其实很喜欢去海滩，很放松，也很有趣。
But I don't really enjoy it going when there are a lot of people.
但我不太喜欢人很多的时候去。
Because I like to relax on the beach.
因为我喜欢在海滩上放松。
But when there are too many people, they're running around, there are kids running around
但人太多时，他们跑来跑去，孩子们到处跑，
and it's not very relaxing.
就不太放松了。
Yeah, I hear you.
是啊，我懂你的意思。
But swimming in the ocean is also very dangerous, right?
但在海里游泳也很危险，对吧？
It can be.
有可能。
So we recommend you go places where there are lifeguards on duty or that you go with
所以我们建议你去有救生员值班的地方，或者和
an expert swimmer.
游泳高手一起去。
Lifeguards.
救生员。
Yeah.
是的。
That's all we've got though for today.
不过今天我们就讲到这里。
We hope you've enjoyed this lesson and we hope you're excited about the upcoming summer
我们希望你喜欢这节课，也希望你对即将到来的夏季
months.
月份感到兴奋。
If you have any questions or comments, please do visit our website EnglishPod.com.
如果你有任何问题或评论，请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好的。
We'll see you guys there.
我们到时候见。
Bye.
拜拜。
All right.
好的。
Man.
天哪。
All right.
好的。